Is your dog friendly
- or just ugly?
- Very friendly!
But, he's not a dog.
I am gonna sue you
for every last... Ah!
Pursuant to...
Good dog.
Tonight's winning number
was approximately six.
Don't most pets eat at
home and poop outside,
like college students?
Nibbler prefers his litter box.
It contains precious sand
with essential minerals
from his home world.
Plus, it's
got nose-numbing crystals.
So, that's why you
never clean it!
Uh, right.
And speaking of
changing the subject,
who wants to see the
new alien language movie
by Bax Glygglif?
I heard it's brilliant!
Ah, sorry. I don't do subtitles.
When I go to the movies,
I don't wanna have to
look up from my phone.
I'd like to see the film, Leela.
Nibbler! You can talk!
You always forget I can talk.
What a romantic movie!
My heart just melted
when Dupdup said...
Although I wasn't crazy
about that big floating head.
It was the best
thing in the movie!
No, no. The one in front
of me, blocking my view.
What's a 2x3x5 letter name
for a 3x23x29 number name
for a movie featuring
a 1x4x9 object?
Easy.
A Space Odyssey.
Aha!
Nibbler, you really are my BFF.
My best furry
friend.
Too corny?
Merely a hairball.
I'm perfectly...
Uh, let's get that looked at.
Well, he seems to have
eaten this endoscope.
But also, he's got worms.
Worms? That's all?
No. That's not all. Let me
finish speaking for once.
The worms are
attacking his brain.
Without treatment, he'll be
left with the IQ of a terrier.
A Boston terrier.
- No!
- Mon Dieu!
Fortunately, there's a cure.
What is it... Sorry.
Ivermectin.
It's a powerful dewormer, okay?
Now, if you're done
interrupting, we're finished.
- Thank you...
- I! Wasn't! Finished!
Just one pill every three hours.
Come on. Open wide.
He won't listen.
His brain's going.
My mom always hid my
medicine in something yummy.
- Like paste.
- That's sad and dumb.
How about cheese?
Yes! Cheese!
Maybe Gouda. Or a nice brie!
How's that medicine working? You
up for a game of Quantum Wordle?
Um, how about something
more deterministic,
like tic-tac-toe?
Tic-tac-toe? FRY: Ooh!
I love that game! You know,
there's a trick to winning.
Always be X.
Would you like to play?
Sure! I'll be O.
You need more medicine,
Nibbler. Want some Manchego?
Make it American.
In individual
plastic-wrapped slices.
- No!
Leela, what's happening to me?
I've been taking all my pills
like a good boy, yet still, I...
I feel my smartness
slipping away.
I don't know, little Fuzzler.
Sad news, everyone.
Oh good, you're already crying.
Nibbler's medicine is killing
the worms in his body,
but they've also infested
the litter box itself.
They reinfect him
every time he uses it.
- Then throw out the litter.
- No!
He needs it to live!
It's from his ancestral
pooping grounds.
Isn't there some other way?
Only one.
But, fortunately,
it's dead simple.
You must shrink down
and battle the worms...
face-to-face!
Really? That sounds gross.
Oh my, yes.
And dangerous.
Oh my, yes!
At least it's dead simple.
That's where you're wrong!
Remember my enlarging ray?
No.
By reversing the lens, it
becomes an all-new kind of ray
that keeps things the same size.
Then, with just a few
minor adjustments...
Voilà!
Shrinking ray!
Once you're in,
you'll kill the worms
with high-powered rifles
loaded with deadly rounds
of liquid ivermectin.
And you'll travel
in this toy tank
I enlarged with
my enlarging ray.
Neat.
- And this track?
- Track?
Oh, right! It
came with the set.
Everybody in.
Enjoy the carnage!
Amy, shove it!
No! You shove it!
Oh. You mean this thing.
Whoopsie-doops!
My Manwich!
Go, baby, go!
Whatever you
do, don't leave the tank.
It's your only protection
against the brutal
desert conditions.
And no screaming!
Poor Nibbler is counting
on us to find those worms,
no matter how grueling the hunt.
Then, we'll need
litter box food.
Maybe we can eat those
weird pygmy hyena moles.
Ow!
Orange sparklies?
Zoidberg's going to
bedazzle his lungs!
Zoidberg?
Are you okay?
- They're coming, why not.
- Who's coming?
I don't know. Maybe those guys?
Stop, or we'll shoot!
Ugh! Blech! They're
attacking! Prepare to fire!
Hang on a sec!
I'm taking a whiz.
At least one of you has manners.
I thank you for your
gift of moisture.
- No problem!
- We've come in search of parasitic worms,
so we can slaughter them
violently. Are you them?
Alas, no.
The sandworms are
our enemies, too.
We are beetles.
Ah, of course. Dung beetles.
It is pronounced Doong.
The G is almost silent.
Welcome to the world of Doon...
g.
The ancient prophecy
speaks of a messiah.
Could he be the
Kwiznos Cadillach?
Nope.
The sun grows hot, and
my deodorant grows weak.
Please, join us in
the Hall of Doong.
I'm gonna try those
big meatballs.
Can I offer anyone some spit?
We have flat and sparkling.
I will have two of each.
The sandworms you
seek roam the desert,
devouring all in their path.
Behold! A map of the universe.
The worms congregate
here, by the great sphere.
But your journey
will be treacherous,
for virtually all paths
end in death.
Then let's just take
the shortest one.
To help you navigate safely,
I must use the glitter chamber,
which allows me to see
all realities at once.
I won't lie, it's pretty cool.
That's what Zoidberg snorted.
Does that make me cool?
Absolutely not!
Only shamans may use
the sacred chamber.
For anyone else, it could
induce a medical-grade freakout!
Like Narlo here.
Dude, I feel like
I'm spinning...
Has anyone seen my...
Oh!
Aha!
Give me that slipper!
Drop it!
Whoa! Oh!
It's ruined!
Bad Nibbler!
I can't help it!
It's those damnable worms!
There, there. I know
what might help.
No! No, I beg of you!
Not the cone of shame!
I see the way.
And I have a serious
craving for frosting.
Mm...
Make a right at the
large sand mound,
then a left at the
medium-sized mound.
After the fifth mound,
you'll see a mound.
So many mounds!
One wrong mound
means certain death.
Or just take the roach-thopter.
Bleh!
Then, you'll need
a guide. Bilgar!
Bilgar is our second-best guide.
Our best guide got
eaten by a sandworm.
Listen to him closely,
and do most of what he says.
The worms are attracted
to the rhythmic pattern
of Doong beetle footsteps.
Whatever you do, do not
walk like a Doong beetle.
Oops!
Even in this
hostile environment,
life thrives.
For example, the
veiny pus fungus.
And the hairless sand pigeon.
Every living creature
here is a total barf bag!
Uh, n-no offense, Bilgar.
These little crawly
guys are cute.
Hello, friends.
That's the
worst one of all!
This final expanse is where
our best guide was devoured.
So, what do we do?
Exactly what he did.
I'll create a diversion
by setting off a pounder.
Hey, you know my
grandfather was a pounder.
It simulates beetle footsteps
to attract the worms.
Go, run!
Don't worry about me.
Our best guy taught
me everything he...
Hey, I guess that makes
me a quarter-pounder.
Oh!
Fry, why don't you have a belt?
Or at least a substantial butt!?
Sorry, guys, I'm a flatty.
Oh, right. Sand.
Hey! Don't bogart that glitter!
- It's coming.
- What's coming?
- A tasty wienerschnitzel?
- A funny monkey?
Sandstorm!
It's hopeless! We
don't have a guide!
We don't know where we are!
The dust is drying out my skin!
Ow!
The sphere! We made it!
Great work, Bender!
This is it. Arm squirt guns!
But we lost that poundy thing
that attracts the worms.
Ah, but we have
Tappy and Shoe-shoe!
They call me the
two-ton Fred Astaire.
Yep. Yep.
The jitterbug?
The litter bug!
He's a dancing machine!
Set squirties to kill!
It's worms within worms!
I am the
God Emperor of Doon... g.
It's them! The parasites that
are making Nibbler stupid!
I know you. You're those worms
that used to live in my tum-tum.
Only you made me smarter.
I'll take your word for it.
Look, you seem like a
nice swarm of maggots,
but you're making my
friend Nibbler sick.
Can't you just infest Zoidberg?
Ew! We prefer to live free,
here among the tumble-turds.
Then prepare for me
to say fire. Fire!
That was my second-best guard!
Worms, form a
defensive squiggle!
Oh...
Good job...
knot!
Whoa...
Look! Up in the sky!
- It's a bird!
- It's a turd!
It's Nibbler!
Stop! Stop fighting!
Okay, I'm done.
Nibbler? Are you alright?
How dumb are you on a
scale of one to Fry?
I can't even count
that high anymore.
But please listen.
I have important things
to say, while I still can.
It is he! The Messiah!
As pictured in the
ancient scripture.
It shows him with blonde
hair and blue eyes,
but the rest is spot on.
I only wish I had more time left
to appreciate this
glittering litter land.
Everywhere I look, I see beauty.
Really? 'Cause I'm seeing poop.
Open your minds
and see as I see.
All life is connected in a
glorious web.
The pus fungus draws
life from the dust
and is eaten by the skin pigeon,
which in turn feeds
the pygmy hyena mole.
Ow... That's cool.
The beetles
process the dung...
It's pronounced doong.
Uh, sorry, Messiah. Keep going.
As for the worms...
well, they feed on my brain.
And that in itself is blutier...
Um, uh, boo-too-poo-pool.
Pretty.
Everything is interconnected.
Everything is perfect.
So please, leave these
worms to play their part,
and I...
I will happily play mine,
even if it means
sacrificing all that I am
and becoming a
mindless house pet.
I accept your gift
of precious liquid.
Finally, you learn some manners.
One last 3D crossword
before your brain
turns to jello?
Alas, my mind has already
degenerated to the point
where I can no longer
predict the ending
of an M. Night Shyamalan movie.
B-But you're
my little Fuzzler.
When all else is gone,
I shall remember that.
Oh, Nibbler!
I know you've made your mind up,
o-or what's left of it,
but please don't let the
worms eat your consciousness!
Now, now, my cherished friend.
Though my mental,
uh, brain may deteriorate,
I will always look back
on what we had with...
big happy.
And you is... be my buddy and...
so, so...
itchy.
Leela, give belly rub.
Aw, Leela, I hate
seeing you like this.
You wanna blow your
nose on my shirt?
Thanks, Fry.
I know this is what
Nibbler wanted,
but I can't wrap
my head around it.
If only I could open
my mind to the beauty
he was blabbering on about.
Please. The chamber is my only
hope of truly understanding!
Well, then find
another only hope.
Pure, uncut glitter
is dangerous.
You could end up
permanently tasting colors.
Or smelling sounds.
I can smell sound.
Fry's singing stinks
up the whole apartment.
Yeah! And if you don't
let Leela use the chamber,
I'm gonna stink up
this whole place.
I feel a song coming on!
Fine! Go nuts.
I see the way.
Everything Nibbler
said was true.
Duh. He's the Messiah.
But he did miss one thing.
He works in mysterious ways.
These parasitic worms should
be making Nibbler smarter,
like when Fry had them.
So why aren't we?
Because the web of life
extends even deeper
than Nibbler perceived.
You worms have been weakened
by sub-parasites!
Oh, that is gross, man!
These tiny mites are sapping
your beneficial juices.
I have been a
little low-energy lately!
I'm feeding on
worm juice with friends!
That's it! I'm out!
Sorry I didn't mention
I was shrinking myself.
You guys must have
been worried sick.
There are levels within
levels within levels.
That's too many levels!
We've gotta kill those mites!
What!? But what about the
precious web of blah-biddy-blah?
You have to draw
the line somewhere.
Stomp those suckers!
Kill 'em all!
It's showtime!
Care to smoosh?
Bender, stop! It's me, Zoidberg!
Sorry! I can't hear your
screams over the tapping!
Dah!
You're gonna be okay.
But what about you, Leela?
You were in that
dangerous glitter chamber.
Did your
senses get scrambled?
Nah, it's fine.
The interwoven
dependency of all things
was the ultimate epiphany.
Yet, thanks to Leela's
unwavering loyalty
and utmost bravery,
my consciousness returned to
ponder another glorious phase
of our universe's evolution.
Good.
You're
my little Fuzzler.
I remember.